{"_gdeSchema_FlashCard":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":""},"1":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Abductive Reasoning","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Abductive Reasoning?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...in the absence of complete information.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Inference to the Best Explanation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"2":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Absurdity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Absurdity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...meaningless life.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"The Absurd","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"3":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Act. vs. Poten. Inf.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"Difference Between Actual and Potential Infinity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Actual Infinity: a completed infinity that exists as a whole, tangible entity (ex: all-natural numbers). Potential Infinity: an infinity viewed as a process that never ends or reaches completion, like the process of counting that continues indefinitely without encompassing all numbers.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Infinitude","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"4":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Adaptation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Adaptation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In biology, how organisms are better suited to their environment as a result of natural selection. More broadly, it can mean adjustments by individuals, groups, or societies to new conditions or environments to improve functionality or success.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Evolutionary Fitness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"5":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetic Distance","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Aesthetic Distance?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Gap between viewer's reality and fictional reality in art. Allows emotional AND intellectual engagement without suspending disbelief. Enables critical appreciation alongside emotional response.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Emotional Engagement","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"6":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetic Experience","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is an Aesthetic Experience?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A type of experience valued for perceptual, emotional, or intellectual engagement with qualities like beauty, harmony, or artistic excellence. Encompasses the appreciation of art, nature, and sometimes everyday objects, emphasizing the role of perception and interpretation in experiencing beauty/artistry.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Artistic Appreciation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"7":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetic Qualities","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Aesthetic Qualities?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Traits of objects, actions, or ideas that make them beautiful, sublime, or artistically valuable. Aesthetic qualities involve sensory, emotional, and intellectual responses to the arts or the natural world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Beauty and Sublimity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"8":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetic Relativism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Aesthetic Relativism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Beauty's subjective; no absolute standards of taste exist. Individual perception or culture determine beauty, not universal rules.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Subjective Taste","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"9":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetic Value","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Aesthetic Value?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The worth/significance an object/experience has based on its capacity to evoke pleasure/appreciation through sensory perception/emotional or intellectual response. Often associated with beauty, artistry, and the sublime, playing a key role in art criticism and aesthetic judgment.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Beauty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"10":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Aesthetics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical study of beauty, art, taste, their creation, and appreciation. Addresses art, beauty, and subjective responses of pleasure.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Sublime","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"11":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Aesthetics Everyday","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Aesthetics of the Everyday?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...sources of aesthetic pleasure and contemplation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Everyday Aesthetics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"12":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Agency","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Agency?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The capacity for individuals to act independently and make their own free choices. Central in sociology, philosophy, and psychology, concerning ability of agents to have power and control over their own lives and the environment around them.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Autonomy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"13":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"AI and Personhood","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is AI and Personhood?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Examines the ethical/legal considerations of granting personhood or legal status to artificial intelligence systems or robots. Includes questions about rights, responsibilities, accountability, and the moral considerations of AI's role in society. Challenges traditional notions of personhood and legal subjectivity.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Artificial Moral Agents","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"14":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"AI Safety","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is AI Safety?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ensuring AI systems are developed and operated safely, ethically, and beneficially. Includes technical research and policy to prevent unintended consequences of AI advancements.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Algorithmic Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"15":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Altered State of Conscious","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Altered States of Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...self-awareness.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Transcendental Experience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"16":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Angst","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Angst?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...responsibility... inevitability of death.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Existential Dread","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"17":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Anthropocentrism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Anthropocentrism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The viewpoint that human beings are the central or most significant species on the planet, often leading to the interpretation or analysis of reality through an exclusively human perspective. This view can justify the exploitation of natural resources and non-human life forms for human benefit.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Human-Centered","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"18":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Anti-Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Anti-Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...independent reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Constructivism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"19":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Antinomies","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Antinomies?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Contradictions arising from seemingly reasonable premises, particularly in philosophy and logic. Kant's famous \"antinomies of pure reason\" are contradictions that cannot be resolved because they stem from the limitations of human understanding.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Paradox","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"20":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Argument Analysis","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Argument Analysis?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The process of evaluating an argument to determine its validity and soundness. It involves identifying the premises and conclusion, assessing the logical structure, and evaluating the truth of the premises and the strength of the inference to the conclusion.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Logical Validity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"21":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Argument Construction","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Argument Construction?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Building a structured case for or against a position, using premises to support a conclusion, based on logic, evidence, and persuasion.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Syllogism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"22":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Arrow of Time","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Arrow of Time?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Time flows in one direction, past to present to future, with entropy increasing (2nd law of thermodynamics). This gives directionality, distinguishing past from future.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Temporal Asymmetry","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"23":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Art for Art's Sake","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Art for Art's Sake?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophy that art has intrinsic value, separate from any moral, didactic, or utilitarian function. Suggests art should be appreciated solely for its beauty and the creation of an aesthetic experience, without being used for any external purpose or message.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Aestheticism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"24":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Authenticity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Authenticity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In philosophy, refers to the degree to which one is true to one's personality, spirit, or character, despite external pressures. In existentialism, it involves living in accordance with self-determined values and beliefs, rather than societal expectations, thereby achieving a genuine mode of existence.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Actualization","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"25":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Autonomy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Autonomy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The ability of a person to act according to objective morality and not just desire/pressure. In moral/political philosophy, linked to self-governance, free will, and the right to determine one's own choices.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Determination","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"26":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Autonomy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Autonomy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The capacity to make an informed, uncoerced decision. Central in ethics and political philosophy, it relates to the self-governing ability of rational individuals and the right to self-determination.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Determination","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"27":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Axiomatic Systems","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Axiomatic Systems?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Formal systems in logic & math based on a set of axioms (basic principles assumed true without proof). From these axioms, theorems and further truths can be logically derived. Provides a clear, unambiguous foundation for the development of mathematical theories and logical reasoning","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Foundationalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"28":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Bad Faith","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Bad Faith (Mauvaise foi)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Self-deception to avoid facing freedom and responsibility, often by adopting false values or denying one's freedom (Jean-Paul Sartre).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Deception","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"29":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Being","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Being?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Fundamental concept in metaphysics, referring to the existence of entities and their presence in the world. Questions about what it means to exist, the nature of objects and their properties, and the distinction between reality and appearance, are central.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Existence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"30":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Belief Revision","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Belief Revision?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The process of changing beliefs when presented with new evidence or information. Belief revision theories explore how to update our beliefs logically and consistently when facing new data contradicting our previous understanding.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Consistency","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"31":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Bias Identification","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Bias Identification?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Recognizing personal, cultural, or systemic prejudices that can affect judgment and decision-making. Crucial for critical thinking and ensuring objective analysis.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cognitive Bias","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"32":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Binary Oppositions","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Binary Oppositions?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...power imbalances...","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deconstruction","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"33":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Biocentric Equality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Biocentric Equality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"All living beings have intrinsic value. No species, including humans, are inherently superior.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Life's Value","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"34":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Biocentrism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Biocentrism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical perspective affirming the intrinsic value of all living beings. Challenges anthropocentric views by placing humans and non-human life on an equal footing, emphasizing that the right to life extends to all biological entities. Calls for a reevaluation of human activities' impact on the natural world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Life-Centered Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"35":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Bioethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Bioethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The study of ethical issues emerging from advances in biology and medicine. It deals with the ethical implications of biological research and applications, especially in medicine, including issues such as cloning, stem cell research, genetic engineering, and patient rights.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Medical Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"36":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Bodily Criterion","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Bodily Criterion?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical concept on personal identity over time. Suggests an individual's identity closely tied to their physical body. According to this criterion, continuity of the same physical body is what fundamentally constitutes the persistence of an individual.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Physical Continuity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"37":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Brain Plasticity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Brain Plasticity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The capacity of the brain to change and adapt in response to experience, learning, or injury. It involves the brain's ability to reorganize itself by forming new neural connections, allowing for functional changes and adaptations throughout an individual's life.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Neuroplasticity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"38":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Business Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Business Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...social responsibility, and fiduciary responsibilities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Corporate Social Responsibility","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"39":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cantorian Set Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cantorian Set Theory?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory of sets by Georg Cantor. Introduced infinite sets, different infinities. Revolutionized mathematics.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cardinality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"40":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Categorical Imperative","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Categorical Imperative?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A central concept in the ethical philosophy of Immanuel Kant, dictating that one should act only according to that maxim whereby you can at the same time will that it should become a universal law. Emphasizes acting out of duty to moral law rather than based on consequences or inclinations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Universalizability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"41":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Caus. & Determinism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Causality and Determinism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Causality refers to the relationship between causes and effects. Determinism is the philosophical theory that all events, including moral choices, are completely determined by previously existing causes. The discussion often centers on determinism's compatibility with free will and moral responsibility.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Fatalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"42":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Causal Theor. of Ref","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Causal Theories of Reference?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Meaning is grounded in a causal link between the word (or its use) and the object it refers to. Connection can be historical or social.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Direct Reference","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"43":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Causality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Causality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The relationship between causes and effects: one event (cause) leads to another (effect). Fundamental in science, philosophy, and logic, it underlies how we understand and interact with the world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cause and Effect","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"44":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Character","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Character?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Set of moral and mental qualities/beliefs distinguishing a person. Includes virtues, values, and personal ethics, shaping behavior/decision-making. The development of good character is considered vital for a moral life.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Virtue Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"45":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cogn. Architecture","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cognitive Architecture?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The underlying structure and processes of the mind that support human cognitive abilities (like perception, memory, language, and reasoning). Cognitive architecture models explain how cognitive processes organize and interact within the mind.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Information Processing","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"46":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cognitive Science","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cognitive Science?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...intelligence and behavior.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mental Representation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"47":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Coherence Theory of Truth","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Coherence Theory of Truth?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...external reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Consistency","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"48":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Coherentism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Coherentism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Epistemological theory: beliefs are justified by their coherence with other beliefs in a system, not by correspondence with empirical evidence or foundational beliefs. Posits justification comes from the mutual support of beliefs within a coherent system.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Belief System","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"49":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Coherentism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Coherentism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...external facts or experiences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Belief System","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"50":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Common Good","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Common Good?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"What is shared and beneficial to all/most in a community (clean air, public spaces, safety).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Collective Well-being","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"51":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Community","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Community?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A group of people living in the same place or having a particular characteristic in common, but also a feeling of fellowship with others, as a result of sharing common attitudes, interests, and goals. Community emphasizes the importance of social bonds and collective well-being.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Cohesion","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"52":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Community Values","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Community Values?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Shared principles, norms, and standards a community holds dear, guiding behavior within the group. Fosters unity, cooperation, and belonging amongst members.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Cohesion","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"53":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Community-Based..","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Community-Based Activism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A form of activism rooted in local communities, focusing on issues directly affecting them. Emphasizes grassroots participation, local knowledge, and collective action to bring about social, environmental, or political change.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Grassroots Movement","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"54":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Compatibilism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Compatibilism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...a universe governed by deterministic laws.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Soft Determinism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"55":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Computation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Computation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Process of using algorithms to transform input data into meaningful output, typically by computers/computational systems. Encompasses mathematical calculations, data processing, and automated reasoning. In broader philosophical context, can refer to theories about computational nature of mind and universe.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Algorithmic Processing","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"57":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Conceptual Schemes","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Conceptual Schemes?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Frameworks (concepts, categories, practices) used by individuals/cultures to structure experience and understand the world. Shapes perception and interpretation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Worldview","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"58":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Consciousness","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Quality/state of awareness of an external object or something within oneself. It encompasses sensations, thoughts, and feelings that are the content of the mind's awareness. The nature of consciousness and how it arises from physical processes in the brain is a central question in the mind philosophy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Phenomenal Consciousness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"59":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Consent of the Governed","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Consent of the Governed?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...by the governed.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Popular Sovereignty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"60":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Consequentialism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Consequentialism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical theory judging actions right or wrong based on their outcomes or consequences. The morality of an action is determined solely by its results. Utilitarianism, which advocates for actions maximizing happiness or well-being, is a well-known form of consequentialism.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Outcome-Based Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"61":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Consequentialism...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Consequentialism (Utilitarianism)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"An ethical theory that judges whether an action is right or wrong based solely on its outcomes. Utilitarianism, a form of consequentialism, argues that the morality of an action is determined by its ability to produce the greatest amount of happiness or pleasure for the greatest number of beings.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Greatest Happiness Principle","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"62":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Constructive Empiricism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Constructive Empiricism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophy of science advocating a pragmatic approach to scientific theories. Says science's aim isn't to find truth, but develop empirically adequate theories accurately predicting and describing observable phenomena.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Empirical Adequacy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"63":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Constructivism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Constructivism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical and educational theory that posits that knowledge and meaning comes from an individual's interactions with their experiences and ideas, rather than being directly imparted from the external world. In international relations, constructivism highlights how social constructs, norms, and institutions shape global politics.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Construction","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"64":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Contex-Depen..Meaning","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Context-Dependence of Meaning?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The principle that the meaning of a statement, word, or expression can CHANGE depending on its context. This context includes the linguistic surroundings, the situation where it's uttered, and the background knowledge of speaker and listeners.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Pragmatic Meaning","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"65":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Contextualism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Contextualism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical theory that a statement's context is vital for understanding its truth, meaning, or appropriateness. Meaning varies based on situation, emphasizing the importance of situational factors.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Relativity to Context","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"66":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Continuity of Conscious","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Continuity of Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...concept addresses how personal identity and self-awareness persist over time.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Stream of Consciousness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"67":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Contractarianism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Contractarianism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Political/moral theory: individuals agree, either explicitly or implicitly, to give up some freedoms and submit to authority in exchange for protection of their other rights. Emphasizes mutual agreement for political and moral order.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Contract","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"68":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Contractarianism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Contractarianism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Political/moral theory emphasizing the role of mutual agreements/social contracts in the foundation of society and moral codes. Argues that moral norms and political arrangements are justified if they result from the consent of those involved, usually to promote mutual benefit and cooperation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Contract","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"69":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Contractualism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Contractualism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical theory viewing morality as based on the social contract, or the agreement among individuals to form a society by mutually accepting certain moral rules or principles. Emphasizes the role of mutual agreement and consent in determining moral obligations and rights.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Consensus","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"70":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Correspondence Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Correspondence Theory of Truth?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Posits that the truth or falsity of a statement is determined by how accurately it reflects the reality it describes. According to this theory, a statement is true if it corresponds to the facts or state of affairs it refers to, linking truth to an objective reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Factuality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"71":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cosmological Argument","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Cosmological Argument?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical argument that God exists. Everything that exists has a cause, and since the universe exists, it too must have a first cause, which is God. This argument is rooted in metaphysical principles of causality and existence and has been formulated by philosophers/theologians like Aquinas and Leibniz.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"First Cause","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"72":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Counter-Storytelling","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Counter-Storytelling?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A narrative technique used to challenge dominant mainstream narratives that often marginalize or silence minority groups' perspectives. Serves as a tool for empowerment, giving voice to those traditionally excluded from the narrative process, to foster a more inclusive understanding of social realities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Narrative Resistance","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"73":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Counterfactuals","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Counterfactuals?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Hypothetical statements of what could have been if circumstances were different. Used for causal reasoning or speculative history. Counterfactuals explore outcomes of alternative scenarios that never actually happened.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Conditional Reasoning","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"74":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Credibility Deficit","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is a Credibility Deficit?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Unfairly perceiving someone's claims or statements as less trustworthy than they merit, often due to bias, prejudice, or stereotypes. Can impact social justice, especially hurting marginalized/disadvantaged groups.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Injustice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"75":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Credibility Excess","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Credibility Excess?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Undue credibility given to individuals/groups, often due to bias, prejudice, or power dynamics. Contrasts with credibility deficits where others are unjustly less credible.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Injustice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"76":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Crit. of Metaphysics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Critique of Metaphysics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"An examination and questioning of the foundations and assumptions of metaphysics, particularly concerning its claims about the nature of reality, existence, and the universe. Critics argue that metaphysical propositions are not empirically verifiable and thus lack meaningful content.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Logical Positivism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"77":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Critical Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Critical Theory?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical approach aiming to understand and critique the power structures and forms of oppression that shape society. Originating with the Frankfurt School, it covers a wide range of issues in culture, economics, and politics, seeking to reveal and challenge underlying power dynamics.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Emancipation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"78":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Critical Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Critical Theory?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical approach seeking to understand, critique, and change society, especially focusing on power structures, inequalities, and cultural ideologies. Originating from the Frankfurt School, critical theory emphasizes the role of culture, economy, and politics in perpetuating dominance and oppression.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Emancipation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"79":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cross-cultural Dial.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cross-cultural Dialogue?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Exchange of ideas/perspectives between people from different cultural backgrounds. Aims to foster understanding, respect, and learning across diverse groups, addressing differences and commonalities. Can challenge assumptions, broaden perspectives, and promote international cooperation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Intercultural Understanding","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"80":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cultural Domination","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cultural Domination?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The control or influence of one culture over others, often leading to minority culture suppression/marginalization. Can result from economic, political, or social dynamics, and plays a big role in shaping cultural identities and practices.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cultural Imperialism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"81":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cultural Globalization","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cultural Globalization?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Transmission and integration of ideas, values, and cultural aspects across the world, increasing interconnectedness/interdependence among cultures. Fosters cultural exchange/understanding but raises concerns about cultural homogenization and the erosion of local cultures and identities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cultural Exchange","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"82":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cultural Pluralism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cultural Pluralism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...coexist and equitably within society.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Multiculturalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"83":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Cybersecurity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Cybersecurity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Protecting systems, networks, and data from digital attacks/theft. Uses technologies, processes, and controls to safeguard against cyber threats.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Information Assurance","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"84":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Death of Author","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Death of the Author?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...irrelevant to interpreting a text.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Reader-Response Criticism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"85":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Death of the Author","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Death of the Author?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Idea by Roland Barthes: author's intentions and biographical context shouldn't dictate a text's interpretation. Focus should be the reader's experience and the text itself as an independent entity. Challenges traditional authorship and encourages open interpretation of texts.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Reader-Response Criticism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"86":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Deconstruction","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Deconstruction?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Critical approach developed by Derrida, aiming to dismantle text/language structures to reveal hidden meanings and assumptions. Challenges traditional interpretations and exposes complexity, contradictions, and ambiguities within texts, emphasizing the fluidity of meaning and the instability of concepts.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Textual Analysis","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"87":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Deductive Reasoning","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Deductive Reasoning?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A logical process where the conclusion is based on the concordance of multiple premises (generally assumed to be true). It's reasoning from the general to the specific, where the conclusion necessarily follows from the premises if they are true.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Syllogism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"88":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Deep Ecology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Deep Ecology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...and biocentric equality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Biocentric Equality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"89":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Defl. Theory of Truth","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Deflationary Theory of Truth?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Argues the concept of truth is simpler than traditionally thought. Saying a statement is true doesn't mean it has the property of \"truth,\" it just endorses the statement itself.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Redundancy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"90":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Deliberative Dem...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Deliberative Democracy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Emphasizes decision-making through discussion and debate, rather than simply voting.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Public Sphere","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"91":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Dem. Peace Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Democratic Peace Theory?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Posits that democracies are less likely to go to war with other democracies compared to non-democratic countries. Argues that democratic institutions and norms promote peaceful conflict resolution, transparency, and mutual trust among democratic states.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Democratic Pacifism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"92":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Democratic Participation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Democratic Participation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...democratic systems.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Civic Engagement","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"93":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Demonstratives","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Demonstratives?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Words or phrases used to point to the location of something in space or time relative to the speaker's position, including terms like \"this,\" \"that,\" \"these,\" and \"those.\" Their interpretation often depends on the physical or discourse context.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deixis","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"94":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Deontology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Deontology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical theory suggesting actions are right/wrong based on if they follow rules/duties, even if consequences are negative. Emphasizes intrinsic worth of acts and following universal moral laws/principles. Kant is a prominent deontologist, advocating actions respecting inherent worth.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Categorical Imperative","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"95":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Descriptive Reference","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Descriptive Reference?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...uniquely picks out an individual.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Definite Descriptions","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"96":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Determinism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Determinism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical theory that all events, including moral choices, are completely determined by previously existing causes. Suggests only one possible future exists at any given moment, based on the laws of nature and the state of the universe at that moment.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Causal Determinism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"97":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Digital Divide","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Digital Divide?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The gap between those who have ready access to computers and the internet, and those who do not. This divide is significant because it affects individuals' ability to participate fully in society, the economy, and politics, potentially leading to inequalities in education, health care, and employment opportunities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Information Inequality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"98":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Digital Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Digital Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Explores ethical issues arising from the use and development of digital technologies. Addresses topics such as privacy, data protection, cybersecurity, digital rights, and the ethical implications of AI & machine learning. Seeks guidance for responsible behavior & ensuring tech serves society.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Information Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"99":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Direct Action","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Direct Action?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A form of political activism that seeks to directly address injustices or social issues without going through official channels/legislative processes. Strikes, sit-ins, blockades, etc. all aim to force change through direct confrontation/intervention.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Civil Disobedience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"100":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Direct Democracy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Direct Democracy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"People decide on policy initiatives directly, without intermediaries/representatives. Citizens vote on laws and policies directly, rather than electing officials to make those decisions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Popular Sovereignty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"101":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Direct Reference","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Direct Reference?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Posits that certain expressions (proper names, natural kind terms) refer directly to objects without a needed description/sense. According to this theory, the meaning of a directly referring term is the object it refers to, simplifying how language connects with reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Rigid Designators","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"102":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Direct vs. Indirect...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Direct vs. Indirect Speech Acts?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Direct speech acts match intent (\"Close the window\"). Indirect acts imply intent less directly, often as polite requests (\"It's cold in here\").","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Implicature","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"103":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Discourse","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Discourse?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...social context.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Discursive Practices","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"104":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Distributive Justice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Distributive Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Concerns the fair and just distribution of goods, resources, and wealth among individuals in a society. Deals with questions about what is considered a fair share, how resources should be allocated, and the criteria used for distribution, such as need, merit, or equality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Equity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"105":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Divine Hiddenness","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Divine Hiddenness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A concept in theology/philosophy of religion, pondering why a loving, powerful God would not make His existence clearer to all people. His hiddenness is seen as challenging belief and faith, especially given suffering and unbelief.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"The Silent God","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"106":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Dualism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Dualism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The belief that reality consists of two fundamentally different components: often the mind and body, or material and spiritual. In philosophy of mind, dualism posits that mental phenomena are, in some respects, non-physical, and distinct from the physical body.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mind-Body Dualism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"107":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Dualism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Dualism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The philosophical view that reality consists of two fundamentally different kinds of substances: mental and physical. In the context of mind-body dualism, it posits that the mind and body are distinct and separable entities, each with different properties.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mind-Body Problem","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"108":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Duties of Care","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Duties of Care?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral/legal obligations to ensure others' welfare and avoid harm. In ethics, it means actions and attentiveness to others' needs, especially for dependent or vulnerable individuals.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Fiduciary Responsibility","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"109":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ecofeminism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ecofeminism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Movement blending ecological concerns with feminist perspectives. Argues exploitation of nature and oppression of women are linked and must be addressed together. Advocates for environmental protection and social justice.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Interconnectedness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"110":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ecological Self","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Ecological Self?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...natural world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deep Ecology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"111":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Economic Globalization","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Economic Globalization?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The increasing interdependence and integration of national economies through growth of international trade, investment, and capital flows. Involves the global spread of goods, technology, information, and jobs across national borders, often driven by multinational corporations and trade agreement reduction.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Global Market","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"112":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Economic Justice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Economic Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Fairness in economic policies and practices impacting how wealth and resources are distributed in society. Addresses income inequality, labor rights, and access to resources, aiming for equal opportunities and outcomes for all.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Distributive Justice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"113":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Eidetic Reduction","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Eidetic Reduction?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...experiences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Essence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"114":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Electoral Systems","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Electoral Systems?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Methods by which votes are translated into seats in the legislature or other governing bodies. Determines how elections/voting are conducted, how votes are counted, and how winners are determined. Common systems include first-past-the-post, proportional representation, and ranked-choice voting.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Suffrage","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"115":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Embodied Cognition","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Embodied Cognition?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory in cognitive science saying the body shapes the mind. Cognitive processes are deeply influenced by bodily interactions with the world. This challenges the traditional model that the mind is a disembodied system operating independently of the physique.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Somatic Mind","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"116":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Emergent Props.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Emergent Properties?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Characteristics or features arising when a complex system operates as a whole, which can't be predicted based solely on its individual parts. These properties reflect the idea that the whole is greater than the sum of its parts, often seen in biological, social, and physical systems.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Synergy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"117":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Emotivism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Emotivism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"An ethical theory suggesting that moral judgments express emotional responses and are not about objective properties of actions or things. Emotivism posits that saying something is \"good\" or \"bad\" is essentially expressing one's feelings about it, rather than stating a fact.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Expressivism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"118":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Empiricism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Empiricism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical stance emphasizing that knowledge comes primarily from sensory experience. Argues that observation and experimentation are the bases for understanding the world, contrasting with rationalism, which posits that reason is the primary source of knowledge.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Sensory Experience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"119":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Envir. Aesthetics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Environmental Aesthetics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Studies how we perceive and appreciate the natural environment. Challenges traditional art-focused aesthetics by finding beauty and value in landscapes, ecosystems, and broader nature itself, not just human-made creations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Natural Beauty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"120":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Environmental Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Environmental Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The philosophy considering the moral relationship between humans and the natural world. Addresses ethics of human action towards the environment, rights of non-humans, conservation of resources, and the duty to combat environmental degradation. Challenges anthropocentrism, promotes eco-centrism/biocentrism.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deep Ecology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"121":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Environmental Justice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Environmental Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people regardless of race, color, national origin, or income related to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws, policies, and regulations. Addresses disproportionate impact of environmental hazards on minority/low-income populations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Environmental Equity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"122":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Environmental Racism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Environmental Racism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Minority group neighborhoods (primarily people of color and economically disadvantaged) bear a disproportionate burden of hazards, including toxic waste facilities, garbage dumps, and other sources of environmental pollution and foul odors that lower the quality of life.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Environmental Injustice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"123":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Epistemology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Epistemology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The branch of philosophy concerned with the theory of knowledge. Explores the nature, origin, scope, and limits of human knowledge, including what knowledge is, how it is acquired, and how we can differentiate between true/false beliefs.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Theory of Knowledge","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"124":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Epoch\u00e9","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Epoch\u00e9?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Term from ancient Greek philosophy, notably used by Husserl in phenomenology, referring to the suspension of judgment about the natural world. It's the methodological step of setting aside assumptions and biases to return to the direct experience of phenomena, allowing for a pure description.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Phenomenological Reduction","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"125":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Equity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Equity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The state of being fair and impartial. In social and economic contexts, equity involves creating conditions that allow everyone to achieve their potential by correcting imbalances and ensuring fair treatment, opportunities, and outcomes for all, regardless of their background.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Justice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"126":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Essence","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Essence?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...character.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Quiditty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"127":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Essence vs. Existence","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Distinction...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Essence = intrinsic nature/quality determining something's identity; Existence = state of being real/alive. Philosophy (like existentialism) explores if the essence of things precedes their existence (traditional view) or existence precedes essence, meaning individuals define their own essence through living.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Existential Priority","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"128":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Eth. Particularism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ethical Particularism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The stance that moral judgment must be made by considering the specifics of each situation, rather than through fixed principles. What is morally right or wrong depends on context.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Contextualism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"129":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Eth. Universalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ethical Universalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Belief that universal ethical standards apply to everyone, regardless of culture, race, gender, or nationality. This argues for the existence of objective moral truths that can guide human behavior in any context.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Absolutism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"130":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ethical Dilemmas in Aid","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Ethical Dilemmas in Aid?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...respect the autonomy of those receiving aid.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Complexity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"131":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ethical Egoism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ethical Egoism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory that actions maximizing self-interest are morally proper. Differs from psychological egoism (a descriptive claim of inherent self-serving behavior). Ethical egoism argues self-serving action is morally correct.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Interest","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"132":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The branch of philosophy concerned with questions about morality and the guiding principles of right and wrong behavior. Examines how individuals ought to act towards each other and the rationale for making moral judgments. Offers different theories and approaches like consequentialism, deontology, and virtue ethics.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Philosophy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"133":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ethics of Ambiguity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Ethics of Ambiguity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical work by Simone de Beauvoir that explores the existentialist view of ethics as a constant project of defining ourselves and our responsibilities in our ambiguous world. Emphasizes freedom, choice, and recognizing interconnectedness in ethical decision-making.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Existential Responsibility","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"134":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ethics of Aut.Systems","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Ethics of Autonomous Systems?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical considerations of machines working independently without human oversight. Concerns include responsibility, privacy, security, and the potential impact on society and employment.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Agency","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"135":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ethics of Care","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are the Ethics of Care?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral philosophy emphasizing interpersonal relationships and care as fundamental. Differs from rights/duties-focused ethics, highlighting the moral importance of caring and nurturing practices.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Relational Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"136":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Eudaimonia","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Eudaimonia?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Aristotelian concept of human flourishing. Highest good achieved through virtuous living and fulfilling potential.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Human Flourishing","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"137":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Evidence Evaluation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Evidence Evaluation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Critically assessing information to judge reliability, validity, and relevance to a claim. Essential for reasoned judgments and informed decisions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Justification","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"138":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Evidentialism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Evidentialism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...justified in believing something based on the evidence.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Empirical Justification","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"139":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Evolution","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Evolution?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The process by which different kinds of living organisms developed and diversified from earlier forms throughout history. Driven by mechanisms like natural selection, genetic drift, and gene flow, it explains life's complexity and the adaptation of organisms to their environments.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Natural Selection","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"140":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Exist. Prec. Essence","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Existence Preceding Essence?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A fundamental concept of existentialist philosophy, particularly associated with Jean-Paul Sartre, positing that individuals first exist, encounter themselves, and emerge into the world without any predetermined essence or purpose. It asserts that individuals define their own essence through their actions and choices.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Authenticity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"141":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Existential Dread","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Existential Dread?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A deep, unsettling feeling of anxiety or despair about one's existence or the meaninglessness of life. This form of dread can arise from confronting fundamental questions of existence, freedom, isolation, and mortality, often explored in existential philosophy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Angst","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"142":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Existential Freedom","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Existential Freedom?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Emphasizes individual self-determination despite constraints. Responsibility comes with freedom to define oneself and values authentically.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Radical Freedom","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"143":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Existentialism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Existentialism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Emphasizes individual freedom and choice. We give our otherwise meaningless lives meaning.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Authenticity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"144":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Explanatory Gap","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Explanatory Gap?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...give rise to subjective experiences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Qualia","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"145":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Externalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Externalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In philosophy of mind and epistemology, the theory that the content of one's mind or justification of one's beliefs depends significantly on factors outside the person's head. Contrasts with internalism, which says mental states or justifications are determined by internal factors only.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Contextual Determinants","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"146":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Fairness","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Fairness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Impartial and just treatment without favoritism or discrimination. Fundamental in ethics and justice, underpinning principles of equality, rights, and responsibilities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Equity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"147":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"False Consciousness","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is False Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...status quo...","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ideology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"148":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Falsifiability","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Falsifiability?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Criterion (introduced by Popper) for determining the scientific validity of a theory. A theory is considered scientific if it can be tested and potentially refuted by evidence. Emphasizes the importance of empirical testing and the ability to disprove hypotheses.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Empirical Testability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"149":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Felicity Conditions","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Felicity Conditions?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Requirements for speech acts (especially performatives) to be effective \u2013 speaker authority, sincere intention, context fitting the act, etc.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Contextual Appropriateness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"150":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Feminist Epis.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Feminist Epistemology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Branch of epistemology examining how gender influences our understanding of knowledge, truth, and the knowing process. Challenges traditional epistemological assumptions/methodologies, arguing they often reflect male biases, and seeks a more inclusive and socially situated approach.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Situated Knowledge","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"151":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Fideism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Fideism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical/theological doctrine arguing for the superiority of faith over reason in religious belief matters. Holds faith is necessary for understanding/accepting religious truths, which cannot be attained through logical or empirical evidence alone. Often emphasizes reliance on divine revelation over intellectual inquiry.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Faith Over Reason","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"152":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Formalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Formalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In philosophy/art, emphasizes form over content/context when analyzing, interpreting, creating works. In math/logic, focuses on formal systems, symbols, and rules, less so their real-world application.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Aesthetic Autonomy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"153":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Foundationalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Foundationalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Epistemological theory asserting that knowledge should be built upon certain, indubitable beliefs. These beliefs are self-evident, empirical, or logically necessary, and all other beliefs should be justified based on them to ensure stability and coherence in the structure of knowledge.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Basic Beliefs","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"154":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Free Will","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Free Will?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The ability of agents to make choices free from certain kinds of constraints. Its existence and nature are debated in philosophy and religion. Questions include whether will is predetermined by natural or divine forces, and how free will can coexist with determinism and moral responsibility.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Autonomy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"155":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Freedom","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Freedom?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The right or ability to act, speak, or think as one chooses without restraint. A fundamental concept in philosophy, politics, and ethics, often divided into \"freedom to\" (positive freedom) and \"freedom from\" (negative freedom).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Autonomy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"156":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Functionalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Functionalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...what they are made of.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Multiple Realizability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"157":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Fusion of Horizons","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Fusion of Horizons?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"From hermeneutics (particularly Gadamer), refers to the process of understanding through merging interpreter's perspective with the historical context of what is being interpreted. Emphasizes the dynamic interplay between the familiar and the foreign, leading to a deeper understanding across differences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Dialogical Understanding","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"158":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Gender and Sex","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Distinction Between Gender and Sex?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Sex refers to biological characteristics (chromosomes, hormones, anatomy) defining humans as male or female. Gender is a social construct related to societal norms, behaviors, and roles associated with being male or female. Gender ID is how individuals perceive themselves, which can be the same as/different from sex at birth.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Gender Identity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"159":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Gender Performativity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Gender Performativity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A concept by Judith Butler. Gender is constructed through repetitive performances in line with societal norms, not a fixed attribute or innate quality. Challenges the binary view of gender, highlighting society's role in shaping identity.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Performative Acts","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"160":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Global Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Global Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The study of ethical issues with global significance (such as environmental sustainability, global justice, human rights, and economic inequality). Seeks to address these challenges by advocating for ethical principles and values that transcend national and cultural boundaries.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cosmopolitanism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"161":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Global Justice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Global Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Application of justice principles on a global scale, addressing inequality, human rights, environmental sustainability, and economic fairness among nations/peoples. Seeks to understand and rectify injustices that transcend national boundaries, advocating for equitable distribution of resources and opportunities worldwide.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cosmopolitanism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"162":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Hard Problem...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Hard Problem of Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The difficulty of explaining why/how we have subjective experiences (\"phenomenal consciousness.\"). Challenges physicalist explanations of the mind, questioning how physical processes of the brain give rise to subjective experiences of color, taste, pain, and the like.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Qualia","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"163":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Hermeneutic Circle","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Hermeneutic Circle?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Describes the process of understanding a text/phenomenon by iterating between its parts and the whole. Understanding the whole arises from reference to individual parts and vice versa. This concept is foundational in hermeneutics, emphasizing the interconnectedness of interpretation and context.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Interpretative Dynamics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"164":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Hermeneutical Injustice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Hermeneutical Injustice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...have their experiences dismissed by others.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Marginalization","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"165":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Hermeneutics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Hermeneutics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The theory and methodology of interpretation, especially texts (religious, literary, philosophical). Expanded to interpret any text, symbol, or expression, emphasizing the importance of context, history, and intention in understanding meaning.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Exegesis","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"166":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Human Enhancement","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Human Enhancement?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Application of technology & science to improve physical, cognitive, and emotional capabilities beyond the normal human range. Includes genetic modifications, cybernetic implants, and biochemical interventions aimed at transcending human limitations and enhancing human abilities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Transhumanism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"167":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Human Rights","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Human Rights?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Rights inherent to all humans, regardless of race, sex, nationality, ethnicity, language, religion, or any other status. Include the right to life and liberty, freedom from slavery and torture, freedom of opinion and expression, the right to work and education, and many more. Human rights are universal and inalienable.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Inalienable Rights","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"168":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Humanitarian Interven.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Humanitarian Intervention?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Use of force or other coercion by one or more countries/international organizations to prevent or end widespread and grave violations of human rights in another state, without that state's permission. Raises complex ethical, legal, and political questions about sovereignty, non-intervention, and responsibilities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Responsibility to Protect","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"169":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Idealism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Idealism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical theory that posits reality, or reality as we can know it, is fundamentally mental, mentally constructed, or otherwise immaterial. Idealism asserts that the mind or spirit is the essence of reality, and the material world is secondary or even illusory.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Phenomenalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"170":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Identity Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Identity Theory?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In philosophy of mind, asserts mental states = brain states. Each mental experience has an identical, specific physical brain state. Materialistic approach to consciousness and the mind.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mind-Brain Identity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"171":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ideology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ideology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A set of beliefs, values, and ideals shared by a group or society, explaining how things should work, and providing political and cultural blueprints for social order. It encompasses a wide range of political, social, and moral perspectives and attitudes, often used to justify/challenge the status quo.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Worldview","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"172":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Illocutionary Act","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is an Illocutionary Act?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...perform actions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Speech Act Theory","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"173":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Illusion","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Illusion?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...the nature of reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Perceptual Misinterpretation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"174":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Incompatibilism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Incompatibilism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical stance that free will and determinism cannot both be true. If determinism holds, actions aren't free. If we have free will, not all events are determined.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Determinism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"175":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Indexicals","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Indexicals?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Indexicals are words or phrases that cannot be fully understood without additional contextual information. Examples: \"I\", \"you\", \"here\", \"there\", \"now\", \"then\". Their meaning depends on when and who is uttering them.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deictic Expressions","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"176":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Individual Rights","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Individual Rights?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Basic legal and moral entitlements afforded to everyone, protecting freedom and ensuring fair legal treatment. Includes freedom of speech, right to privacy, right to a fair trial, freedom from discrimination, and more. Foundational to liberal democracies and human rights frameworks.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Civil Liberties","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"177":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Inductive Reasoning","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Inductive Reasoning?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Method of reasoning where generalizations come from observed patterns or specific examples. Unlike deductive reasoning (general premises to a specific conclusion), inductive reasoning moves from specific observations to broader generalizations with conclusions that are probable, not certain.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Empirical Generalization","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"178":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ineffability...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Ineffability of Relig. Exps?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Religious/mystical experiences are beyond language's ability to describe. Such experiences are too profound or transcendent to be entirely captured in words.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mystical Experience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"179":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Infinity in Cos/Phys","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Infinity in Cosmology and Physics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The concept plays a crucial role in cosmology and physics, particularly about the size of the universe, black hole behavior, and theoretical foundations. Raises questions about the universe's boundaries, the nature of space and time, and the potential for infinite parallel universes.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Singularity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"180":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Institutional Racism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Institutional Racism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Policies, practices, and procedures of institutions with a disproportionately negative effect on racial minorities' access to goods, services, and opportunities. Unlike individual racism, it's embedded in societal institutions (legal, education, healthcare, law enforcement), perpetuating racial disparities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Systemic Discrimination","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"181":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Institutions","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Institutions?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...social interactions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Order","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"182":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intent. vs. Exten.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Distinction Between...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In logic and semantics, intension = internal content of a concept (the necessary/sufficient conditions for something to fall under it). Extension = the external range of objects that it applies to (the set of things it refers to).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Connotation vs. Denotation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"183":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intentional Fallacy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Intentional Fallacy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The erroneous belief that an artwork's meaning/value relies on the artist's intent rather than the audience's perception/interpretation. W.K. Wimsatt and Monroe Beardsley introduced the idea, arguing that a work should stand independently of its creator's intentions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Authorial Intent","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"184":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intentionality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intentionality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Quality of mental states that are about, or directed towards, something. Fundamental to phenomenology and philosophy of mind, it describes how thoughts, beliefs, desires, and perceptions can be about objects, events, or situations in the world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Aboutness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"185":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intercult. Philosophy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intercultural Philosophy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A branch of philosophy that seeks to go beyond the perspective of any one culture, exploring philosophy across different cultures. It emphasizes dialogue between cultures to enrich philosophical understanding and address global challenges.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cross-Cultural Dialogue","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"186":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intergenerational...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intergenerational Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Focuses on fairness in distributing resources, opportunities, and burdens between present and future generations. Raises ethical questions about sustainability, environmental stewardship, and the legacy left for future inhabitants of Earth.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Sustainability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"187":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intergenerational...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intergenerational Equity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Principle of fairness between current and future generations. Concerns rights of future people to natural resources, a healthy environment, sustainable planet. Central to environmental ethics and policy, emphasizes sustainable development to not compromise the ability of future generations to meet their needs.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Sustainability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"188":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Internalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Internalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In epistemology, this view is that the justification of one's beliefs lies within one's own mental states, accessible to the subject's awareness. Contrasts with externalism, which holds that factors external to the subject's mental states can contribute to the justification of beliefs.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Justification","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"189":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Interp. of Q. Mech.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Interpretation of Quantum Mechanics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Various philosophical interpretations attempt to explain quantum mechanics' abstract and counterintuitive mathematical formalism. These interpretations seek to understand the nature of quantum entities, the meaning of wave function collapse, the role of the observer, and the implications for the nature of reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Copenhagen Interpretation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"190":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Interpellation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Interpellation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Marxist theory concept (by Louis Althusser) on how individuals become subjects through ideologies. It describes how ideology calls out to or \"hails\" individuals, positioning them within a specific social and ideological framework.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Subject Formation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"191":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Interpretivism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Interpretivism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...objective.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hermeneutics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"192":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intersectionality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intersectionality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...systems of oppression and domination.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Multidimensional Identity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"193":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intersubjectivity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intersubjectivity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Shared, mutual understanding between individuals, based on their common experiences and exchanges. Crucial in philosophy and social sciences for the establishment of meanings, norms, and a shared reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Cohesion","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"194":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intrinsic Value","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intrinsic Value?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Value something has \"in itself,\" or \"for its own sake,\" independent of its usefulness/utility to anyone/anything else. Contrasts with instrumental value (valued for utility in achieving something else). Intrinsic value is key in ethics, aesthetics, and environmental philosophy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ends in Themselves","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"195":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Intuitionism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Intuitionism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophy in ethics and mathematics. Says truth isn't derived from empirical evidence but intuitive knowledge or understanding. In ethics, moral truths are known through immediate intuitive insight. In math, it emphasizes proofs based on intuition, rejecting the law of excluded middle for infinite collections.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Intuition","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"196":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Is-Ought Problem","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Is-Ought Problem?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The question (raised by David Hume) of moving from descriptive statements (what \"is\") to prescriptive statements (what \"ought\" to be). Hume argued you cannot derive an \"ought\" just from an \"is\", revealing a logical gap between describing the world and prescribing how it should be.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hume's Guillotine","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"197":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Justified True Belief","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Justified True Belief?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Traditionally how knowledge was defined. A person knows a proposition if and only if: it's true, the person believes it, and the person's belief is justified. This has been debated, particularly since Edmund Gettier's challenge, presenting scenarios where JTB exists without what we'd call knowledge.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Gettier Problem","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"198":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Justified True Belief","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Justified True Belief?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A traditional concept in epistemology that defines knowledge as a belief that is both true and justified. According to this theory, for someone to know something, there must be a true proposition, the person must believe in the proposition, and there must be sufficient evidence or reasons supporting the belief.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"199":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Land Ethic","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Land Ethic?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory proposed by Aldo Leopold extending the boundaries of ethics to include land and ecosystems. Suggests humans view themselves as part of the natural community rather than its conquerors, promoting respectful and ethical use of our natural resources.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ecological Conscience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"200":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Lang. of Thought Hyp.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Language of Thought Hypothesis?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Cognitive science theory: thought occurs in a mental language (\"Mentalese\"). The brain processes information using complex symbols and rules, similar to language.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mentalese","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"201":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Language Analysis","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Logic and Language Analysis?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical study of how language is used in logical reasoning and argumentation. Examines the structure of arguments, meaning & use of words, and how linguistic expressions relate to the world. Seeks to clarify how language can accurately convey truth and facilitate understanding.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Analytic Philosophy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"202":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Leap of Faith","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Leap of Faith?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Concept by S\u00f8ren Kierkegaard, referring to the act of believing in something without sufficient empirical evidence, especially in regards to religious faith. Emphasizes the importance of personal commitment over rational proof in matters of faith.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Existential Commitment","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"203":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Legal Rights","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Legal Rights?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Entitlements granted to individuals by law. Can be civil, political, economic, or social in nature and include rights such as the right to free speech, the right to privacy, and the right to a fair trial. Ensure protection and fair treatment under the law and are enforced by legal institutions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Jurisprudence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"204":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Liberal Democracy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Liberal Democracy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Government combining democratic governance with protection of individual liberties and rights through the rule of law. Emphasizes free and fair elections, separation of powers, protection of civil liberties, and minority rights.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Constitutional Democracy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"205":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Liberation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Liberation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The act of gaining freedom from oppression, limitation, or control. In philosophical and political sense, liberation often involves overcoming social, economic, and political constraints, in search of individual autonomy and collective emancipation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Emancipation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"206":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Libertarianism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Libertarianism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Political philosophy emphasizing individual liberty as the key principle. Advocating for minimal government intervention in citizens' lives (especially economic), it argues for free markets, property rights, and voluntary associations. Values personal freedom/autonomy, often opposing coercive action by the state beyond protecting individual rights.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Non-Aggression Principle","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"207":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Limits of Human Reason","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Limits of Human Reason?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The boundaries beyond which rational thought, logical analysis, and empirical investigation cannot offer definitive answers or understanding. Explores inherent limitations of human cognition in comprehending the universe, nature of consciousness, and the foundations of morality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Humility","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"208":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Linguistic Relativity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Linguistic Relativity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The idea that the structure of language affects its speakers' worldview or cognition. Suggests language influences thought and cultural practices, leading to variations in perception and experience across different linguistic communities. Also called the Sapir-Whorf hypothesis.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Whorfian Hypothesis","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"209":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Locutionary","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is a Locutionary Act?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The act of saying something with specific meaning in a particular context. Encompasses uttering words, their conventional meaning, and the referential content of the utterance. It's one aspect of the broader speech act, as defined by J.L. Austin, along with illocutionary and perlocutionary acts.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Speech Act Theory","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"210":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Logic","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Logic?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The study of reasoning and argumentation. Analyzes arguments for validity, and soundness, using a systematic approach to evaluate propositions and conclusions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deductive Reasoning","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"211":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Logic of Identity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Logic of Identity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A fundamental principle in logic and philosophy asserting that an entity is identical to itself and different from anything else. It deals with conditions under which something is considered the same as or different from another thing.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Leibniz's Law","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"212":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Logical Fallacies","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Logical Fallacies?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Errors in reasoning that invalidate an argument. Seemingly convincing but fail under scrutiny. Includes ad hominem attacks, straw man arguments, false dilemmas, circular reasoning.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Faulty Reasoning","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"213":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Logical Paradoxes","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Logical Paradoxes?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Statements or propositions that contradict themselves or lead to situations defying intuition. Challenge our understanding of concepts like truth, reference, and logical validity. Examples include the Liar Paradox, Russell's Paradox, and the Barber Paradox.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Reference","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"214":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Logicism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Logicism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Belief that math can be reduced to logic, and thus mathematical truths are logical truths.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Principia Mathematica","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"215":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Logocentrism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Logocentrism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Tendency to regard words and language as a fundamental expression of external reality, privileging speech as a direct conduit to meaning/truth. Derrida criticizes this for ignoring language's inherent ambiguity and the way meaning is deferred and constructed through differences between signifiers.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Phonocentrism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"216":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Longtermism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Longtermism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Prioritizes the well-being of future generations. Suggests influencing the long-term future is a key moral duty.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Future Generations","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"217":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Machine Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Machine Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Involves the design and implementation of ethical principles and values into artificial intelligence systems and robots. Focuses on creating machines capable of making moral decisions and acting ethically in various situations, addressing concerns about AI's impact on society.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Artificial Moral Agents","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"218":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Many-Worlds Interp...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Many-Worlds Interpretation...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"One interpretation of quantum mechanics that posits the universe splits into many unobservable branches when a quantum measurement is made. Each possible outcome occurs, but in a separate parallel universe. This eliminates the need for wave function collapse and resolves some paradoxes in quantum physics.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Parallel Universes","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"219":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Market Free vs Reg.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Market Freedom vs. Regulation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The debate between allowing markets to operate with minimal government intervention versus implementing regulations to correct market failures, protect consumers, and promote social welfare. Proponents of market freedom argue for economic efficiency and choice, while advocates of regulation emphasize fairness and protection.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Laissez-faire","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"220":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Materialism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Materialism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The philosophical stance that all phenomena (including mental phenomena and consciousness) are the result of material interactions. Denies immaterial substances, positing the physical world is the only reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Physicalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"221":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Mental States","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Mental States?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Conditions or processes of the mind, including thoughts, feelings, beliefs, desires, and intentions. Central to discussions in the philosophy of mind and psychology, relating to consciousness, identity, and the mind-body problem.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Consciousness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"222":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Meta-ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Meta-ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Examines the nature, scope, and meaning of moral judgments/language. Addresses questions about origins/status of ethical principles, objectivity of moral claims, moral reasoning, and the meaning of ethical terms. Unlike normative ethics, meta-ethics focuses on underlying assumptions about morality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Semantics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"223":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Metaph. of Identity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Metaphysics of Identity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The branch of metaphysics exploring the concept of identity and what it means for something to be the same as, or different from, something else over time. Includes discussions on the persistence of objects, persons, and entities, and the conditions under which they remain identical or change.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Persistence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"224":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Metaphys. Impli. S-T","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are the Metaphysical Implications...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Space & time as one 4-D continuum (rather than separate) has profound implications for how we understand the universe, causality, the past/present/future... challenging traditional metaphysical beliefs about time and space.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Continuum","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"225":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Metaphysics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Metaphysics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Branch of philosophy concerned with the fundamental nature of reality, including the relationship between mind and matter, substance and attribute, and potentiality and actuality. It seeks to answer questions about existence, objects and their properties, space and time, cause and effect, and possibility.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ontology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"226":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Method. Indiv. vs. Hol.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"The Debate Between...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Methodological individualism: social phenomena are accurately explained only by showing how they result from individual actions/interactions. Holism: social phenomena are best understood by looking at larger social/cultural groups or systems that individuals are part of.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Structures","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"227":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Microaggressions","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Microaggressions?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...based solely on their group membership.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Subtle Discrimination","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"228":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Mind Uploading","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Mind Uploading?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Hypothetical process of scanning and mapping a conscious mind onto a computer system, allowing for a digital continuation of consciousness independent of the biological brain. Raises profound questions about identity, consciousness, and the nature of the self.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Digital Immortality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"229":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Mind-Body Problem","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Mind-Body Problem?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Fundamental question in the philosophy of mind about the relationship between mental phenomena (thoughts, emotions, consciousness) and physical phenomena (brain and body). Explores how mental and brain states are related, and the nature of consciousness.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Dualism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"230":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Modal Logic","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Modal Logic?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Extends logic to include concepts like necessity, possibility, etc.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Necessity and Possibility","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"231":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Modality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Modality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In philosophy, deals with possibilities, necessities, and impossibilities. Encompasses concepts like possibility, necessity, and contingency, exploring how things could, must, or cannot be, across different possible worlds or scenarios.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Possible Worlds","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"232":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Modularity of Mind","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Modularity of Mind?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...distinct modules that operate semi-autonomously.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cognitive Modules","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"233":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Agency","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Agency?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The ability of a person to make moral judgments based on the concepts of right and wrong, and be held accountable for their actions. Moral agents can act with reference to right and wrong and have a responsibility to ensure their actions are ethical..","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Accountability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"234":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Anti-Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Anti-Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The view there are no objective moral values. Moral statements don't report facts, thus can't be true/false.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Subjectivism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"235":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Anti-Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Anti-Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...challenges the objectivity of moral judgments.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Subjectivism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"236":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Dilemmas","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Moral Dilemmas?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Situations where decision must be made between two or more morally conflicting actions, making it difficult to find the right course of action. Moral dilemmas test our values, ethics, and ability to prioritize principles.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ethical Paradox","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"237":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Education","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Education?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The process of teaching individuals to recognize, analyze, and act ethically. Develops moral reasoning, ethical understanding, and virtuous character traits, preparing individuals to handle complex moral landscapes in personal and social situations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Character Development","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"238":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Objectivism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Objectivism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Asserts universal moral truths exist, applying to all, independent of culture or belief. These truths exist regardless of human recognition.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Universal Morality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"239":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Particularism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Particularism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral judgment depends on situational details, not universal principles. Context decides an action's moral relevance. Ethical decision-making should be flexible and responsive to the specific circumstances.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Contextual Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"240":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical position asserting that ethical statements refer to objective features of the world, independent of human opinion. For moral realists, moral facts exist and can be true/false, and our moral judgments can be accurate/inaccurate based on them.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ethical Objectivity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"241":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Relativism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Relativism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...universal moral standards.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cultural Relativism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"242":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Responsibility","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Responsibility?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The state of deserving praise, blame, reward, or punishment based on moral obligations. Depends on having the capacity for informed decisions and control over actions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Accountability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"243":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Rights","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Moral Rights?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...creator's honor or reputation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Authorial Integrity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"244":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Standing...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Moral Standing of Animals and Plants?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Refers to the ethical consideration and value assigned to non-human life forms. Debates whether/how animals/plants have rights, deserve protection, and should be considered in moral decision-making, challenging anthropocentric views of ethics.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Biocentrism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"245":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Moral Subjectivism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Moral Subjectivism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"View that ethical values and judgments are merely a matter of individual/cultural preferences and feelings, rather than reflecting objective truths. According to this perspective, ethics are not about discovering external moral facts but are subjective and can vary between persons or cultures.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ethical Relativism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"246":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Morality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Morality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Involves differentiating intentions, decisions, and actions between those that are proper vs. improper. Morality can be based on standards/principles derived from a particular philosophy, religion, or culture, or based on a standard that a person believes should be universal.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ethical Principles","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"247":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Multiculturalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Multiculturalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Political/social policy promoting acceptance and preservation of different cultural identities within a society. Encourages coexistence of diverse cultures, dialogue, and mutual respect between them.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cultural Pluralism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"248":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Mutual Aid","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Mutual Aid?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Individuals/groups work cooperatively to meet each other's needs, challenging competition.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cooperation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"249":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Mysticism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Mysticism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Involves the pursuit of achieving communion with God/ultimate reality. Characterized by direct experiences, intuition, or insight aiming for union with the divine or the cosmos. Traditions across the world describe mystical experiences as transcending usual human consciousness and involving unity with the divine.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Transcendental Experience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"250":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Natural Rights","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Natural Rights?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Fundamental rights inherent to humans, independent of laws, customs, or beliefs. They are universal and inalienable, including life, liberty, and the pursuit of happiness.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Inalienable Rights","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"251":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Natural Selection","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Natural Selection?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...generations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Survival of the Fittest","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"252":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Nature of Phys. Laws","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Nature of Physical Laws?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A fundamental question in philosophy of science about what physical laws are and how they function. Are they mere descriptions of natural regularities, or do they possess a prescriptive or necessitarian character governing physical objects' behavior? Debates causality, determinism, and scientific explanation's limits.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Necessitarianism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"253":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Nature of Soc. Facts","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Nature of Social Facts?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Concept by sociologist \u00c9mile Durkheim. Values, cultural norms, and social structures that transcend individual preferences and are capable of social control. Aspects of social life shaping our actions as members of society, independent of our individual wills.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Collective Consciousness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"254":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Neg. vs. Pos. Liberty","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Difference Between...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Negative liberty: freedom from interference by others, highlighting absence of obstacles/barriers. Positive liberty: the possibility to act to take control of one's life and realize one's fundamental purposes. Negative focuses on external constraints, positive on conditions necessary for personal development/autonomy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Freedom To vs. Freedom From","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"255":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Neural Correlates...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are the Neural Correlates of Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The minimal set of neuronal events and","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"256":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Neutrality/Impartiality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Neutrality and Impartiality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Neutrality \u2013 not taking sides. Impartiality \u2013 fairness, free of bias/favoritism. Both are crucial for ethical decision-making, mediation, and justice, so decisions are made without prejudice.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Equitability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"257":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Non-Classical Logics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Non-Classical Logics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Variants of logic that deviate from classical logical norms to address limitations and expand applicability. Non-classical logics, such as modal, intuitionistic, and fuzzy logic, explore alternatives to traditional binary truth values, enabling more nuanced or specific reasoning.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Modal Logic","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"258":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Non-Evidentialism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Non-Evidentialism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Belief in some things (like religious faith) can be rational even without empirical evidence. Not all beliefs need evidence to be considered meaningful.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Faith","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"259":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Non-Identity Problem","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Non-Identity Problem?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical dilemma about actions that change the identity of future people without harming them, as those people wouldn't have existed otherwise. Challenges traditional notions of harm and responsibility when decisions affect future generations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Future Persons","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"260":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Norms","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Norms?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Informal understandings governing the behaviors of members within a society. They represent social expectations and guidelines for acceptable behavior, helping to maintain order and cohesion. Norms vary widely across cultures and contexts and can be reinforced through sanctions or rewards.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Conventions","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"261":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Numerical Identity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Numerical Identity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The concept that an entity is identical to itself and distinct from all others. Involves the principle of indiscernibility of identicals - if two objects share all the same properties, they are considered to be one and the same object.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Leibniz's Law","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"262":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Numinous Experience","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is a Numinous Experience?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Type of religious/spiritual experience with the feeling of the presence of something wholly other, transcendent, or divine. Often associated with awe, wonder, and a sense of the sacred. Linked to Rudolf Otto's \"mysterium tremendum et fascinans,\" the awe-inspiring mystery attracting and repelling simultaneously.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mysterium Tremendum","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"263":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Objectivity in SS","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Objectivity in Social Science?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Principle in social science of observing, analyzing, and interpreting social phenomena based on facts without bias. Aims for unbiased conclusions through systematic, transparent, and replicable methodology, but full objectivity is challenging due to the subjective nature of human society, and the influence of researchers' perspectives.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Methodological Rigor","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"264":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Objects and Properities","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Nature of Objects and Their Properties?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...and their roles in the creation of reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ontology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"265":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Obligation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Obligation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A duty or requirement to act a certain way, often morally, legally, or socially grounded. Encompasses responsibilities individuals or institutions have towards others or society as a whole.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Duty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"266":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Onto. of Abs. Ent.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Ontology of Abstract Entities?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The study of the nature and existence of abstract entities like numbers, properties, sets, and concepts. Looks at whether abstract entities exist independently of the physical world and how they can be known or understood.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Platonism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"267":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ontol. of Understanding","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Ontology of Understanding?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The study of being and existence as it relates to comprehension and interpretation. Examines how conceptual frameworks shape how we understand reality and how these frameworks inform our interactions with the world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hermeneutic Ontology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"268":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ontological Argument","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Ontological Argument?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical argument for God's existence based on the very concept of God implying His existence. First by Anselm of Canterbury, argues God, defined as the greatest conceivable being, must exist, as existence is a perfection and something not existing can't be the greatest conceivable being.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"A Priori Proof","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"269":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ontological Commitment","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ontological Commitment?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The philosophical stance about which entities or types of entities exist. Commitments a theoretical framework makes about reality, often implied by using certain terms/concepts within the theory.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Existential Assumption","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"270":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ontology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Ontology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Branch of metaphysics dealing with the nature of being, existence, reality. Explores fundamental questions about what entities exist, and how these entities can be grouped, related within a hierarchy, and subdivided.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Being","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"271":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Oppression","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Oppression?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...pursuit of a good life.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Systemic Inequality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"272":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Panpsychism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Panpsychism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The view that consciousness (mind or soul) is a fundamental and pervasive part of the universe. All matter has some form of mental aspect, so even simple materials have some form of consciousness or experience.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Universal Consciousness","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"273":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Paradigms","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Paradigms?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Widely accepted frameworks guiding research and understanding in a field. They determine standards, methods, and objectives of scientific inquiry, influencing how problems are understood and solved.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Scientific Revolution","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"274":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Paradoxes of Infinity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Paradoxes of Infinity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical/mathematical puzzles arising when dealing with the concept of infinity (dividing space/time infinitely, comparing different infinities). Challenges intuitive notions of quantity, size, the finite.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hilbert's Hotel","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"275":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Paradoxes of Motion","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are the Paradoxes of Motion?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Challenge the nature of motion/change. Zeno's paradoxes argue motion doesn't exist.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Zeno's Paradoxes","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"276":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Patriarchy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Patriarchy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Social system where men hold primary power and predominate political leadership, moral authority, social privilege, and property control. It entails social, legal, and cultural structures that reinforce and perpetuate male dominance over women and gender minorities.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Male Dominance","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"277":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Perception","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Perception?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The process by which individuals organize and interpret sensory information to represent and understand their environment. It involves the acquisition and processing of sensory data through the interaction of the sensory organs and the brain, leading to an individual's experience of the world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Sensory Processing","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"278":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Performative Utt...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Performative Utterances?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Statements that do something by being spoken \u2013 make promises, bets, apologies, etc. (J.L. Austin). They transform social reality, not just inform.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Speech Act","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"279":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Perlocutionary Acts","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Perlocutionary Acts?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Actions performed via speech that affect the listener's state of mind or actions. Unlike illocutionary (intent to communicate), focuses on impact.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Speech Effect","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"280":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Pers. Religious Exp.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Personal Religious Experiences?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Direct, intimate interactions with a transcendent reality, profoundly impacting individual faith and understanding of the divine. Highly subjective and diverse across cultures and religious traditions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Mystical Experiences","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"281":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Persuasion Techniques","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Persuasion Techniques?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Methods to convince or influence others to change their attitudes, beliefs, or actions. They range from logical argumentation to emotional appeal and play a crucial role in communication, advertising, and rhetoric.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Rhetorical Strategies","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"282":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Phenomen. Method","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Phenomenological Method?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical approach that seeks to describe phenomena as they are experienced directly by consciousness, without using theories, deductions, or assumptions. Developed by Edmund Husserl, it involves \"bracketing\" preconceptions to focus on the pure experience of phenomena.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epoch\u00e9","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"283":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Phenomenological Reduct","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Phenomenological Reduction?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...pure experience.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epoch\u00e9","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"284":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Phenomenology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Phenomenology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Branch of philosophy that studies the structures of experience and consciousness. Founded by Edmund Husserl, it seeks to describe phenomena as experienced from the first-person point of view, emphasizing direct experience and intuition over abstract reasoning or empirical observation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Intentionality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"285":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Philosophical Cosmology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Philosophical Cosmology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The branch of philosophy studying the universe's origin, structure, and dynamics. Questions the nature of the cosmos, possibility of multiple universes, the concept of time, and the governing principles of the universe.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cosmogony","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"286":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Philosophical Pluralism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Philosophical Pluralism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Recognition and acceptance of a diversity of values, methods, and truths in philosophy. Suggests there may be multiple valid perspectives and approaches to understanding the world, rejecting the idea of only one correct philosophical system or set of beliefs.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemological Tolerance","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"287":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Philosophy of Mind","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Philosophy of Mind?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Branch of philosophy studying the nature of the mind, mental events, mental functions, consciousness, and their relationship to the physical body (the brain). Addresses questions about the nature of thoughts, feelings, perceptions, the self, and how physical processes in the brain give rise to mental life.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Dualism vs. Physicalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"288":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Physicalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Physicalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical position: everything existing is no more extensive than its physical properties, and the only true substances are physical. Mental states, properties, and processes are fundamentally physical in nature.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Materialism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"289":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Physicalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Physicalism (Materialism)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical position that everything that exists is no more extensive than its physical properties and that the only true substance is physical matter. It denies the existence of non-physical entities and posits that mental states and consciousness arise from/are explained by physical processes in the brain.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Reductionism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"290":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Play of Signifiers","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Play of Signifiers?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A post-structuralist theory concept (particularly Derrida) referring to the fluid and dynamic relationship between words (signifiers) and their meanings (signifieds). It suggests meanings are not fixed but constantly deferred through an endless chain of signifiers, leading to unstable and multiple interpretations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Differance","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"291":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Pluralism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Pluralism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Acknowledges and accepts diversity within a political body, society, or institution. Varied groups can peacefully coexist, maintaining distinct cultural identities while contributing to the common good.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cultural Diversity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"292":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Political Legitimacy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Political Legitimacy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The right and acceptance of an authority (governing body, law) seen as justifiable by the governed. Often based on consent, justice, the rule of law, or leadership's efficacy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Sovereignty","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"293":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Polluter Pays Principle","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Polluter Pays Principle?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...accountable for environmental harm.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Environmental Accountability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"294":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Popular Sovereignty","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Popular Sovereignty?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The principle that the authority of a state and its government are created and sustained by the consent of its people, through their elected representatives (Rule by the people). It is a fundamental principle of democratic governance, where the people are the ultimate source of political power.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Democracy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"295":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Poss. of Time Travel","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Possibility of Time Travel?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A topic of scientific, philosophical, and literary exploration considering whether it is possible to move between different points in time, like moving through space. Discussions involve implications of relativity theory, causality, and the nature of time itself.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Temporal Paradox","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"296":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Possible Worlds","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Possible Worlds?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Complete, consistent ways the world could have been or might be.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Modal Realism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"297":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Post-Structuralism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Post-Structuralism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical/literary movement that emerged in the mid-20th century in reaction to structuralism. They argue structures of thought and language are inherently unstable and meaning isn't fixed, but instead constructed and deconstructed through language and discourse.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Deconstruction","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"298":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Posthumanism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Posthumanism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical perspective that seeks to transcend traditional notions of what it means to be human, in light of technological advancements and evolving understandings of identity, embodiment, and consciousness. It challenges anthropocentric views and explores the implications of merging humans with technology, artificial intelligence, and biotechnology.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Transhumanism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"299":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Pract. Wisdom (Phr.)","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Practical Wisdom (Phronesis)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Aristotelian concept. The ability to make the right decision about how to act in diverse practical situations. Involves both knowing what to do AND understanding why it's the right action, balancing moral virtues and practical judgment.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ethical Judgement","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"300":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Prag. Theory of Truth","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Pragmatic Theory of Truth?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Truth is based on practicality and usefulness. Beliefs \"work\" if they address problems, guide action, fit coherently in a belief system.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Utility","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"301":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Pre-Understanding","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Pre-Understanding?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Our prior experiences shape how we interpret new information or texts (hermeneutics).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Fore-structure of Understanding","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"302":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Predicate Logic","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Predicate Logic?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...logical structures.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Quantifiers","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"303":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Principle of Div...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Principle of Diversity and Symbiosis?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Concept in ecology and philosophy valuing variety of life and interdependent relationships among different organisms. Posits that biological and cultural diversity are vital for resilience and flourishing of ecological systems and societies, promoting mutual benefit and cooperation.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ecological Interdependence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"304":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Principle of Utility","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Principle of Utility?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Key concept in utilitarian ethics: the best action is the one that maximizes utility, usually defined as the greatest well-being of the greatest number of people. It evaluates the ethicality of actions based on their consequences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Greatest Happiness Principle","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"305":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Priv. Lang. Argument","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Private Language Argument?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical argument presented by Ludwig Wittgenstein, suggesting that a language understandable by only a single individual is not coherent. It implies that language fundamentally needs public criteria for meaning and verification, challenging the notion of purely personal linguistic understanding.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Language Games","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"306":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Privacy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Privacy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...individual autonomy and personal dignity.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Informational Self-Determination","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"307":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Privilege","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Privilege?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Special right, advantage, or immunity granted or available only to a person or group. Discussed in sociology and philosophy in terms of systemic inequalities benefitting certain groups over others, based on race, gender, class, or other social categories.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Advantage","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"308":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Prob. Other Minds","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Problem of Other Minds?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical dilemma about how to justify our belief in the existence of minds other than our own. Questions if we can truly know that others have minds and experiences similar to ours, considering we can only observe external behaviors, not internal mental states directly.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Solipsism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"309":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Problem of Evil","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Problem of Evil?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"How can an all-good, all-powerful God exist alongside the world's suffering? Challenges justifications for God's ways (theodicies), raising deep questions about faith, free will, and God's nature.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Theodicy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"310":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Problem of Universals","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Problem of Universals?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Do universals (properties, types, relations like \"redness\") exist? If so, how are they related to individual instances? Debates center on how real they are.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Platonism vs. Nominalism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"311":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Procedural Justice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Procedural Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...stakeholders.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Due Process","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"312":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Process Philosophy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Process Philosophy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A philosophical approach that emphasizes becoming and change over static being. Views reality as fundamentally of processes rather than enduring substances, highlighting the dynamic and interrelated nature of the universe.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Becoming","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"313":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Professional Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Professional Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral principles and conduct standards for specific professions. Includes obligations to clients, the public, and other professionals, often codified in ethical codes.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Code of Conduct","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"314":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Propositional Content","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Propositional Content?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Informational content of a statement - the true-or-false thing it asserts. This is distinct from specific wording, and can be believed, questioned, etc.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Assertion","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"315":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Propositional Logic","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Propositional Logic?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A branch of logic that studies ways of joining and/or modifying entire propositions to form more complicated propositions, as well as the logical relationships and properties that follow from these methods.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Logical Connectives","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"316":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Psychological Criterion","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Psychological Criterion?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory that personal identity over time lies primarily in psychological continuity (memory, personality, intentions, consciousness), not purely physical continuity.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Psychological Continuity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"317":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Qualia","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Qualia?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Subjective, individual experiences of perception & sensation (e.g., redness of a rose, pain of a headache). Intrinsic, private, only accessible to the experiencer. Central to discussions in the philosophy of mind about consciousness and the nature of experience..","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Phenomenal Experience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"318":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Qualitative Identity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Qualitative Identity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Similarity or sameness in terms of qualities, features, or properties between two or more entities. Unlike numerical identity (entities must be identical in every way), qualitative identity allows for comparing entities based on attributes, even if they're not the exact same object.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Similarity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"319":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Quantum Mechanics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Quantum Mechanics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...locality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Superposition","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"320":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"R2P","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Responsibility to Protect (R2P)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Global political commitment by UN member states (2005) to prevent genocide, war crimes, ethnic cleansing, crimes against humanity. Holds states responsible for protecting their populations from these crimes, mandates international community to intervene appropriately when they can't.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Humanitarian Intervention","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"321":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Radical Env-ism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Radical Environmentalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"An environmental movement advocating for significant changes to human behavior and societal structures to protect the environment. Emphasizes direct action, ecological ethics, and sometimes confrontational tactics to prevent environmental harm and promote sustainability.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Eco-activism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"322":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Rational Choice Theory","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Rational Choice Theory?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Economic principle assuming individuals always make prudent/logical decisions providing the highest amount of personal utility. Decisions are self-interested with the expectation that everyone involved behaves rationally.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Utility Maximization","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"323":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Rationalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Rationalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical position that reason is the main source and test for knowledge, or that reality itself has an inherently logical structure. Posits truths exist that can be known a priori, independently of sensory experience. This stands in contrast to empiricism, which emphasizes sensory experience as the source of knowledge.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"A Priori Knowledge","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"324":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Real. vs. Anti-Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"Difference Between Moral Realism and Anti-Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral Realism: Belief that objective moral truths exist independently of how we perceive them. Moral Anti-Realism: Denies that moral values/truths exist independently of our beliefs or attitudes, suggesting moral claims don't refer to objective features of the world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Objective/Subjective Morality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"325":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The viewpoint that the existence of reality is independent of our conceptual schemes, perceptions, linguistic practices, beliefs, etc. Realists assert there are entities and truths that exist independently of our knowledge/perception of them. Can apply to metaphysics, ethics, and science.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ontological Independence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"326":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Realism vs Anti-Realism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Realism vs. Anti-Realism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Realism asserts that there's an objective reality independent of human perception/beliefs. Anti-realism denies this, proposing our sensory experiences, concepts, or language form the fundamental nature of reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Objective Reality/Constructivism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"327":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Reality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Reality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The state/quality of having existence or substance in the physical world (not imaginary/conceptual/fictional). Philosophical discussions about reality explore: the nature of being/existence, the relationship between perception and the external world, and the distinctions between physical and metaphysical realms.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Ontology","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"328":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Reasoning","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Reasoning?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...conclusions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Logical Inference","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"329":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Recognition","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Recognition?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Acknowledgment and respect for rights, autonomy, and achievements of individuals/groups. Crucial in social/political theory, emphasizing recognition of identities, contributions, and rights within society. Vital for personal development, social inclusion, and justice.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Acknowledgment","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"330":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Reference","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Reference...?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Relationship between linguistic expressions and the real-world entities they denote. How words/symbols/signs relate to objects, actions, concepts outside of language itself, crucial in understanding meaning and communication.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Denotation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"331":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Refutation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Refutation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Disproving or countering an argument or a statement with evidence, logic, or reasoning. Critical tool in debates, discussions, and philosophical inquiry, aimed at challenging and clarifying opinions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Counterargument","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"332":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Relativity of Space/Time","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Relativity of Space and Time?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...space-time.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Space-Time Continuum","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"333":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Reliabilism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Reliabilism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"An epistemological theory suggesting that beliefs are justified if produced by processes that tend to lead to true conclusions. Emphasizes the reliability of the cognitive processes, NOT the specific beliefs themselves.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cognitive Reliability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"334":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Representation","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Representation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The action of speaking or acting on someone's behalf. Also, the depiction of something in art, literature, or media. In politics, officials acting on behalf of constituents. In arts/philosophy, it explores how objects, ideas, and emotions are depicted/symbolized.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Symbolism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"335":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Responsibility","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Responsibility?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The state or fact of having a duty to deal with something or of having control over someone. In ethics and philosophy, it involves the obligation to act correctly and be accountable for one's actions, emphasizing the moral duty to perform tasks and roles according to societal norms or personal principles.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Accountability","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"336":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Retributive Justice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Retributive Justice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory of justice holding that punishment for crimes should be proportional to the offense committed. Based on the principle of just desert (people get what they deserve). Emphasizes retribution or punishment as a form of moral reparation, aiming to balance scales, rather than rehabilitation or deterrence.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Just Desert","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"337":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Right to a...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Right to a Healthy Environment?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The concept that individuals are entitled to a clean, safe, sustainable environment. Increasingly recognized in international law/national constitutions, it underlies efforts to protect nature, fight pollution, address climate change.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Environmental Justice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"338":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Rights Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Rights Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Branch of moral philosophy focused on the rights of individuals and the duties others have to respect those rights. Asserts some rights are fundamental and untouchable, forming the basis for moral judgments and legal protections.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Inalienable Rights","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"339":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Rights of Fut. Gen.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Rights of Future Generations?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The ethical consideration that present actions should not compromise the ability of future generations to meet their own needs. Focuses on environmental protection, sustainable development, and intergenerational justice, highlighting our responsibility to preserve resources and the environment for those yet to come.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Intergenerational Equity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"340":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Rights of the Displaced","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Rights of the Displaced?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Refers to rights and protections afforded individuals forced from their homes due to conflict, persecution, natural disasters, or development projects. Includes refugees, internally displaced persons, and asylum seekers, focusing on their rights to safety, asylum, and humane treatment.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Forced Migration","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"341":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Robot Rights","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Robot Rights?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical/legal considerations of granting rights/protections to robots, especially with advanced AI/autonomy. Debate includes issues of personhood, moral/legal responsibility, and rights of robots versus obligations of humans towards them.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Artificial Moral Agents","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"342":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Role of the State","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Role of the State?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The duties and responsibilities of the state to its citizens, including maintaining order, protecting the rights and safety of individuals, providing public services, and promoting the general welfare. Philosophical and political debates often center on the extent and limits of state power and intervention in the lives of citizens.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Governance","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"343":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Roles","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Roles?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The expected behaviors, rights, obligations, responsibilities, and privileges assigned to social positions or statuses within a society. They guide how individuals are supposed to act and interact based on their social positions, contributing to social order and predictability.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Script","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"344":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Sapir-Whorf Hypothesis?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...reality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Linguistic Determinism (Linguistic Relativity)","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"345":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Scientific Revolutions","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Scientific Revolutions?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...observed phenomena.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Paradigm Shift","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"346":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Sem.-Prag. Distinction","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Semantics-Pragmatics Distinction?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A differentiation between semantics (the study of meaning of words and sentences on their own) and pragmatics (the study of how context influences meaning). Linguistics and the philosophy of language focus on this distinction.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Contextual Meaning","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"347":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Sense","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Sense?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...point to).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Intension","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"348":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Set-Theoretic Paradoxes","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Set-Theoretic Paradoxes?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...contradiction.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Russell's Paradox","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"349":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Shared Relig. Exp.","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Shared Religious Experiences?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Collective encounters with the divine or sacred that occur within a community or group of believers, strengthening communal bonds and shared beliefs. These experiences can be ritualistic, ceremonial, or spontaneous and create a sense of common understanding of the divine.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Communal Worship","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"350":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Ship of Theseus","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Ship of Theseus Paradox?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Thought experiment questioning identity and change. If all parts of Theseus' ship are gradually replaced piece by piece, is it still the same ship? Challenges our understanding of what it means for an object to remain the same despite changes over time.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Identity Over Time","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"351":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Singularity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Singularity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...poses new, unforeseen risks.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Technological Singularity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"352":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Skepticism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Skepticism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical attitude questioning the possibility of certain/absolute knowledge. It challenges the reliability of claims without sufficient evidence, emphasizing critical thinking and doubt. Skepticism can be applied broadly, from questioning the existence of the external world to challenging the veracity of sensory experience or other knowledge claims.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Methodological Doubt","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"353":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Social Constr. of Race","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Social Construction of Race?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Theory that race is not biologically determined but created and developed by society. Emphasizes that racial differences are created through social interactions and history, leading to systemic inequalities and stereotypes.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Racialization","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"354":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Social Equality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Social Equality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Equal rights, opportunities, and resource access for all in a society, regardless of background. Efforts to reduce disparities in wealth, education, and power are central.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Equity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"355":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Social Equity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Social Equity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...just society.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Justice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"356":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Social Hierarchy","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Social Hierarchy?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"System of social organization where individuals or groups are ranked one above another based on status, authority, or another criterion. Hierarchies are present in almost all societies and can be based on factors including economic status, class, ethnicity, or gender.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Class Stratification","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"357":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Social Identity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Social Identity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Individual's sense of self based on their group membership(s) (national, religion, culture, social). Social identity theory suggests part of one's self-concept derives from the groups they belong to, influencing behavior and how they're perceived by others.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Group Affiliation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"358":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Social Stratification","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Social Stratification?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The division of society into hierarchical layers based on wealth, income, status, occupation, power, etc. Results in unequal resource/opportunity access, affecting lifestyles, behavior, and social interactions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Class Hierarchy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"359":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Solidarity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Solidarity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Unity of feeling or action, especially within a group with a common interest. Mutual support is key. Often used in social/political movements to emphasize shared goals and collective responsibility.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Communal Bonds","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"360":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Sovereignty","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Sovereignty?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Full right and power to govern oneself without outside interference. In political theory, it's the supreme authority within a territory, embodying total independence and self-governance.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Autonomy","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"361":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Space as Void/Plenum","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Debate Between Void vs Plenum?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical/scientific debate about the nature of space. Void concept = empty container where things exist and move. Plenum concept = fully extended substance or field inherently filled with matter or energy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Vacuum/Ether","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"362":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Space-Time","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Space-Time?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A four-dimensional continuum in which all physical events take place. The theory of relativity shows space and time aren't independent dimensions, but interwoven into a single fabric curved by mass and energy. This concept fundamentally changes our understanding of the universe, the nature of gravity and the flow of time.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Relativity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"363":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Species","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is a Species?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A group of similar organisms capable of exchanging genes/interbreeding. The principal natural taxonomic unit, ranked below genus, denoted by a Latin binomial.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Biological Classification","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"364":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Speciesism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Speciesism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The assumption of human superiority leading to animal exploitation. Involves discriminating against beings based on their species membership, often ignoring their ability to suffer or their interests. Used in animal rights discussions for equal consideration of all sentient beings.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Anthropocentrism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"365":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Speech Acts","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Speech Acts?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Actions performed through speaking. Developed by J.L. Austin and Searle, it asserts that saying something is doing something. Acts are locutionary (saying something), illocutionary (intending something by saying it), and perlocutionary (affecting someone by saying it)","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Performativity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"366":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"State of Nature","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the State of Nature?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A hypothetical concept in political philosophy, describing human conditions before or without political association and civil society. Used to theorize the origins of society, the nature of humanity, and the justification of political authority.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Social Contract","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"367":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Statelessness","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Statelessness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"When a person is not considered a national by any state under its law, resulting in a lack of legal recognition and protection. Contributes to social and economic exclusion.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Right to Nationality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"368":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Storytelling","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Storytelling?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The social and cultural activity of sharing stories, often with improvisation, theatrics, or embellishment. Storytelling is an ancient form of communication and plays a significant role in history, education, and entertainment, conveying values, beliefs, and lessons across generations.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Narrative","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"369":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Struc. Epis. Injustice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Structural Epistemic Injustice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A form of injustice happening when social structures prevent certain groups from fully participating in practices of knowledge production and sharing. Involves systematic issues that devalue and silence contributions from marginalized communities, impacting their ability to be recognized as credible knowers.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Exclusion","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"370":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Superintelligence","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Superintelligence?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...indistinguishable from human intelligence.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Artificial General Intelligence (AGI)","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"371":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Sust. Technology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Sustainable Technology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Technology designed to use energy and resources more efficiently and with reduced environmental impact, aimed at meeting our needs without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs. Encompasses renewable energy, green manufacturing, and eco-friendly materials.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Green Tech","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"372":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Sustainability","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Sustainability?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Principle of meeting present needs without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their own needs. Encompasses environmental, social, and economic dimensions, aiming for a balance between human activity and preservation of the natural world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Triple Bottom Line","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"373":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Syncretism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Syncretism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The blending of different religions/cultures/ schools of thought. Combining practices and beliefs from multiple systems into a new, cohesive whole. Common in religious practice, philosophical doctrines, and cultural traditions.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cultural Fusion","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"374":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Syndicalism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Syndicalism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"An economic and political theory advocating for the control of industries and businesses by worker-led syndicates or unions. Promotes direct action and the management of society through networks of federated unions, aiming for a cooperative economy and the abolition of the wage system.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Workers' Self-Management","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"375":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Technological Det...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Technological Determinism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The theory that technology development drives societal changes, shaping cultural values, social structures, and history. Posits that technological advancements are the primary factor influencing human societies and their development.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Technocentrism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"376":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Technology & Equity","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Technology and Equity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Examines how tech advancements can either promote or hinder fair access to resources and opportunities across different social groups. Focuses on the fair distribution of tech's benefits and mitigating its potential to worsen inequality.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Digital Divide","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"377":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Teleological Argument","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Teleological Argument?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...an intelligent creator.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Design Inference","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"378":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Teleology in Biology","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Teleology in Biology?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Teleology is the explanation of phenomena by their purpose, rather than by postulated causes. In biology, it involves understanding structures and processes in terms of their evolutionary purposes or functions, explaining why organisms have developed adaptation traits over time, focused on survival and reproduction.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Functional Explanation","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"379":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Teletransportation Paradox","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Teletransportation Paradox?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...over time.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Personal Identity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"380":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Testimonial Injustice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Testimonial Injustice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"When a speaker's credibility is unfairly deflated due to prejudice, leading to an unfair distribution of credibility. It's a form of epistemic injustice that can silence or marginalize individuals and groups, preventing them from full participation in communication.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Injustice","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"381":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Textual Int...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Textual Interpretation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Determining the meaning of texts (literature, law, sacred texts). Involves various methods and theories, from literal to critical analysis, considering context, authorial intent, and the reader's response to uncover multiple layers of meaning.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hermeneutics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"382":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Textuality","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Textuality?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The quality defining a text as a structured set of symbols and meanings meant for interpretation. Encompasses how texts are made, interpreted, and understood in cultural/social contexts.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Intertextuality","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"383":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Common Good","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Common Good?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophy, ethics, and pol. sci. concept about what is shared and beneficial for everyone in a community. Involves promoting the community's welfare as a whole and is often used to justify moral and political decisions aimed at benefiting everyone, rather than individual interests.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Public Interest","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"384":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Commons","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are The Commons?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Shared resources a community has rights to, including natural resources (forests, oceans, atmosphere) plus cultural and intellectual properties. Managing commons needs collective action and responsibility to ensure they remain available for generations to come.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Collective Stewardship","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"385":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Lifeworld","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Lifeworld (Lebenswelt)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The \"world\" as lived in everyday experience (Husserl). Includes relationships, culture, history. Background setting for all conscious acts.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Pre-reflective","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"386":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Lifeworld","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Lifeworld (Lebenswelt)?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A concept in phenomenology (Husserl, Habermas) referring to everyday, pre-reflective experience. Encompasses the background environment of capabilities, practices, and attitudes that individuals take for granted in daily life, forming the basis for all communication and understanding.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Pre-reflective Experience","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"387":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Self","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Self?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Refers to an individual's consciousness of their own identity and personal characteristics. Encompasses their thoughts, experiences, and perceptions of being as a distinct, continuous entity over time. Philosophical discussions explore its nature, existence, and development.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Personal Identity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"388":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Sublime","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is the Sublime?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Quality of greatness or grandeur beyond calculation, measure, or imitation. In aesthetics, describes inspiring awe/wonder because of vastness, beauty, or power. Associated with nature and art that evoke profound reactions, transcending ordinary experience.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Transcendence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"389":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"The Virtues","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are the Virtues?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral qualities or traits considered desirable or morally good, such as courage, justice, wisdom, and temperance. Virtue ethics focuses on developing characteristics constituting a good and fulfilling life, emphasizing moral character over rules or actions' consequences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Aretaic Ethics","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"390":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Theories of the Self","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Theories of the Self?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical concepts, frameworks exploring the nature, essence, and existence of the self or personal identity. Questions include consciousness, personal continuity over time, the self-body relationship, and the construction of personal identity.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Self-Identity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"391":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Theory-Ladenness...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Theory-Ladenness of Observation?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The idea that what we observe and how we interpret it is influenced by our pre-existing knowledge, beliefs, and theoretical assumptions. Challenges the notion of objective or theory-neutral observation, suggesting scientific data and empirical observations are always interpreted through a theoretical lens.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Paradigm","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"392":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Time: A vs. B","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"The Debate Between A-Theory and B-Theory of Time?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"A-Theory suggests time is tensed, meaning past/present/future are objectively different. B-Theory posits time is tenseless, with all points equally real and the distinctions a matter of perspective. A aligns with common human experience, B with physics' spacetime model.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Temporal Realism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"393":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Time/Space Continuum","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Continuum of Time and Space?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Foundational concept in physics and philosophy. Time and the three dimensions of space are inseparable, with events happening in a four-dimensional continuum. Central to the theory of relativity, it revolutionized our understanding of how time and space interact.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Space-Time","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"394":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Undecidability","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Undecidability?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Concept in logic and math referring to problems that cannot be definitively resolved as either true or false within a given formal system. Highlights the limits of certain systems of logic or computation to provide conclusive answers to all questions posed within them.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"G\u00f6del's Inc. Theorems","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"395":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Underdet. of Theory...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Underdetermination of Theory by Data?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophical concept that any set of empirical data can have multiple theories explaining it. Highlights limits of empirical evidence in conclusively proving a single theoretical explanation is correct. Emphasizes role of additional criteria (simplicity, coherence, explanatory power) in theory choice.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Epistemic Ambiguity","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"396":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Underdetermination","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Underdetermination?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Philosophy of science principle: a given body of evidence can support multiple, often competing, theories. Suggests empirical data alone can't definitively conclude one theory is more valid, highlighting the role of theoretical and methodological choices in scientific inquiry.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Empirical Equivalence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"397":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Unity of Consciousness","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is The Unity of Consciousness?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Despite the diversity of sensations, thoughts, and feelings, the mind integrates these into a single, unified conscious experience. This concept explores how disparate mental states coalesce into a coherent sense of self and how we perceive the world.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cohesive Self","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"398":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Universal Beauty","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Universal Beauty?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...common to human beings.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Aesthetic Universals","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"399":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Universal Values","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What are Universal Values?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical/moral standards widely accepted across cultures as essential or true. These values (justice, peace, equality, respect for human dignity, etc.) are believed to apply to everyone, everywhere, transcending cultural differences.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Universals","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"400":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Universality vs. P...","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Universality vs. Particularity?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Debate on whether moral principles are universal (applying to everyone) or particular (dependent on context).","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Relativism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"401":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Utilitarianism","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Utilitarianism?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Ethical theory proposing actions are right if they promote happiness/pleasure, and wrong if they produce unhappiness/pain. Form of consequentialism, focusing on outcomes to gauge morality. Central to the thought is the greatest happiness principle, maximizing good for the most people.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hedonistic Calculus","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"402":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Utility","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Utility?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"In economics and philosophy, the satisfaction or benefit derived from consuming goods or services. In ethical theory (particularly utilitarianism), it's the measure of goodness/value of outcomes, often defined in terms of happiness or well-being.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Hedonic Calculus","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"403":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Vice","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Vice?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Moral failings or bad habits detrimental to oneself or others. Seen as the opposite of virtue in discussions of ethics and philosophy.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Corruption","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"404":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Virtue","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Virtue?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Characteristic deemed morally good, valued as a foundation of good moral being. Virtues guide our actions and decisions aligning with ethical principles and are key to the concept of character in moral philosophy","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Moral Excellence","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"405":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Virtue Ethics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Virtue Ethics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"...mean between vices of excess and deficiency.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Eudaimonia","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"406":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Voluntary Association","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is a Voluntary Association?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Group of individuals who voluntarily enter into an agreement to form a body to accomplish a purpose. Ex: clubs, charities, trade unions. Include a shared mission/interest, self-governance, and a lack of governmental/external control.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Civil Society","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"407":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"Welfare Economics","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is Welfare Economics?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Studies optimal resource allocation and how that affects social welfare.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Pareto Efficiency","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"408":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"White Privilege","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is White Privilege?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"Unearned benefits individuals perceived as white receive in society due to systemic racism and discrimination. Manifests in various areas including education, employment, legal systems, and social interactions. May be invisible to those who benefit from it.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Systemic Advantage","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"},"409":{"_gdeType_QuestionTip":"String","QuestionTip":"World Citizenship","_gdeType_Question":"String","Question":"What is World Citizenship?","_gdeType_Answer":"String","Answer":"The idea that one's identity transcends geography/politics, and that responsibilities or rights are derived from membership in humanity itself. Emphasizes global cooperation, peace, and concern for international justice and the well-being of people worldwide, regardless of national boundaries.","_gdeType_AnswerTip":"String","AnswerTip":"Cosmopolitanism","_gdeSchema":"FlashCard"}}